<speak>
<!--
Wordpress articles post: Metadata
   <meta property="og:title" content="" />
    <meta property="og:url" content="" />
    <meta property="article:published_time" content="" />
    <meta property="og:site_name" content="" />
    <meta property="og:image" content="" />
-->
    <metadata>
        <dc:date><dc:date>
        <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
        <dc:source></dc:source>
     <dc:title></dc:title>
    </metadata>
1.05 R<break time="1s" />
		As soon as she slammed the door shut, Ryoka collapsed against her bed. Static seemed to crawl over her eyes and roaring filled her ears.<break time=200ms/>
Pain. It was coming back.<break time=200ms/>
She would have lain there forever, but the pain made her move. There was only one relief.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka staggered over to a chest at the foot of her bed. She fumbled at it and realized it was locked. Key. Where was the damn key?<break time=200ms/>
The static was everywhere and the pain was getting worse. Ryoka had just finished opening the lock when she gagged and nearly threw up. It hurt.<break time=200ms/>
Inside the chest was a roll of odd bandages and several green potions. Ryoka instantly grabbed one and popped the cork.<break time=200ms/>
Sitting with her back against the bed, she stretched out her bad leg as far as she was able. The bandages were red with blood now, and the flesh was beginning to puff up. Shed pushed too far.<break time=200ms/>
Gingerly, blacking out with pain, Ryoka poured the green liquid over her leg and tried not to scream. But the effects were instantaneous.<break time=200ms/>
The painvanished. For an instant, a wonderful instant, all was well. Ryoka watched in blissful peace as the swelling around her leg faded, and below the bandages, the broken skin and torn flesh closed.<break time=200ms/>
But it didnt last. After only a few seconds, pain started to return to the area. Dreadful, biting agony.<break time=200ms/>
The bones. The bits of shattered bones that couldnt be healed. They cut into her flesh and stopped the healing. Ryoka stared down at her leg. It hurt, but far less now. At least, for the moment. She had a few hours to half a day, depending on what she did to her leg before her flesh would <emphasis level="moderate">tear</emphasis> and<break time=200ms/>
The bandages were now completely bloody, but Ryoka didnt dare change them. They were the only things keeping the rest of her leg on her body.<break time=200ms/>
Magic. She sensed it in the cloth bindings. Theyd been whatten gold coins? More expensive than the healing potions, even. But they had magic in the stitching, or so the [Healer] had claimed. And she felt it. They were the only reason she could move about, let alone keep her legintact.<break time=200ms/>
The magic in the bandages provided stability, structure, and stasis. She could actually move about on a leg where she couldnt feel anything below her knee due to the bindings holding her leg in place. And so long as she applied a healing potion every few hours, she could keep the damage from her leg at bay.<break time=200ms/>
But eventually, the magic always wore off. And then the swelling would begin, and if it kept on too long the leg would start to rot.<break time=200ms/>
Magic bandages and healing potions. Ryoka thumped her head back against the footrest of her bed. They could barely keep her injuries in check, but not heal them. What they were really doing was buying time. Time, until she could find a way to heal herself<break time=200ms/>
Or lose the leg.<break time=200ms/>
She couldnt feel it anymore. Rather, it was the broken stump just below her kneecap that screamed agony at her each time she agitated it. But her foot and lower leg?<break time=200ms/>
Nothing.<break time=200ms/>
The [Healer] had told her it was still attached, still living flesh so long as she kept healing it with a potion, but it wasnt about to start healing on its own. It was too badly damaged.<break time=200ms/>
Maybe if there was a surgeon, one from her world. They could have realigned the bones and connected them with metal rods. If shed been in a hospital she would have had a chance. But here?<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka put her face in her hands. Garia kept suggesting better [Healers], or treated her injuries as something that would heal given time. But Ryoka didnt <emphasis level="moderate">have</emphasis> any time left.<break time=200ms/>
What do you think splintered bone means?<break time=200ms/>
Garia didnt get it. But then she hadnt seen Ryokas leg in the moments afterwards. She hadnt seen how it wasnt <emphasis level="moderate">attached</emphasis>, wasnt <emphasis level="moderate">solid</emphasis> anymore. The adventurers understood.<break time=200ms/>
Crushed bone. Splintered bone. Not a break or a fracture. It wasnt like joining two pieces back together. Ryokas right leg was a mass of bone splinters without a chance of reattaching on their own.<break time=200ms/>
Medically, the answer was simple. Until the modern era, there would have been no chance any other way. And even thenher legs wouldnt have ever been the same. Ryoka knew what had to be done. Theyd told her as she sat in shock as the [Healer] poured potions on her leg and tried to save her flesh.<break time=200ms/>
Amputation. Either that or a spell that she couldnt afford.<break time=200ms/>
For a while shed hoped it was just her imagination. Shed bought the bandages from the [Healer], scraped together all the money shed earned so far to buy enough healing potions to last until now, and prayed that her leg would start to heal. But each day passed with blood and pain and no relief.<break time=200ms/>
No one could help her. Ryoka knew that. Garia cared, and even the Horns of Hammerad had stopped by. But what could they do? A hundredno, <emphasis level="moderate">hundreds</emphasis> of gold coins. Why make them worry? Why waste energy reassuring them with useless words?<break time=200ms/>
So Ryoka pretended not to worry and did everything herself. Because of pride. Because she didnt want to appear weak  because that in itself was weakness.<break time=200ms/>
Because there was nothing anyone could do to help her.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka rested her head against her arm. Pain. Cut it away. They said it would be quick. No. But it was the only choice. She hadthree healing potions left. Enough for a day or two. And then shed be out of money and out of time. Unless she could pay. But she had no money.<break time=200ms/>
Well, she knew someone who had thousands, tens of thousands of gold coins, didnt she? Of course. And it could be done. There was still a chance.<break time=200ms/>
But the cost<break time=200ms/>
Ah, the cost.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka closed her eyes. Damnation. That was the cost. And she still wasnt sure if it was worth her leg. Shed thought about it long and hard. And she still wasnt sure. But she wanted to know the cost. And to do that, she had to bargain.<break time=200ms/>
So what Ryoka was really doing, what she was really thinking as she sat in the wet puddle of the healing potion and blood was nothing. Nothing. She could worry, or fret, and she was afraid and in pain, but there was nothing she could really do. All she was doing, in truth, behind everything, was waiting.<break time=200ms/>
Waiting. Waiting for her to arrive. Waiting to make the choice.<break time=200ms/>
In her mind she could feel the wind on her face and feel the ground flying beneath her feet. In her mind she could see the consequences of her choice.<break time=200ms/>
A world burned by fire. The dead lying in piles. War, endless and putrid. That was the cost.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka closed her eyes and tried not to cry.<break time=200ms/>
 <break time=200ms/>
—-<break time=200ms/>
 <break time=200ms/>
It was evening by the time Garia managed to excuse herself from the inn and make her way back to the Runners Guild. By that point shed already imbibed quite a lot of liquid, most of it alcoholic.<break time=200ms/>
Garia had an extremely high tolerance for alcohol, so she only stumbled every now and then as she jogged towards the Runners Guild. She wasnt intending on making a delivery of course; that would be dangerous in the fading light even without being drunk, but she wanted to pick up her payment for the week. She was running low on money after insisting she pay for her meal.<break time=200ms/>
Shed left the rest of the Horns of Hammerad in the semi-destroyed inn, still drinking and talking about how they could help Ryoka. It was strange. Garia had only heard of the Horns as one of the up-and-coming adventurer teams, but she hadnt really believed the rumors about them being honor-bound like their leader.<break time=200ms/>
Well, everyone knew that Minotaurs were supposed to be honorable, but that was hard to believe when you saw one up close. A Minotaurs word was as good as a Knights supposedly, but how did you square that with their cow heads and fierce tempers? But Calruz hadnt been overly violent  hed even paid for all the damage hed caused.<break time=200ms/>
It was strange. The number of non-humans Garia had seen, let alone met she could probably count on both her hands. This far north you didnt see any of the other races, not even Drakes or Gnolls. But Calruz had seemed sosohuman.<break time=200ms/>
And he liked Ryoka. And <emphasis level="moderate">that</emphasis> was something Garia wasnt going to think about. Instead, she was going to open the door to the Runners Guild without falling on her face and walk inside.<break time=200ms/>
Most of the Runners glanced up and then away, ignoring Garia as she entered. She wasnt particularly powerful within the Runners Guild, but she was liked well enough that no one bothered her. That was what Garia preferred. Being unnoticed was safest.<break time=200ms/>
Garia noticed a commotion occurring around the receptionists counter, which made her heart sink. The unnoticed part of her reputation also meant she wouldnt be helped until they sorted out what was going on. Glumly, Garia went to sit down at one of the tables when she heard someone calling her name.<break time=200ms/>
Garia! Hows my favorite City Runner?<break time=200ms/>
Garias heart skipped a beat and then started going into overdrive as she recognized the voice. Fals. She turned around and gave him what she hoped was an annoyed look.<break time=200ms/>
I bet you say that to every Runner, Fals.<break time=200ms/>
Only the ones I like.<break time=200ms/>
Fals walked over and smiled at Garia. He was handsome and tall, and Garia could see several female Runners glaring at her as he approached. She tried not to smile back too quickly.<break time=200ms/>
Are you finished with your deliveries for the day?<break time=200ms/>
Yup. Nothing too special; I did a few trips to Lindol and back, but thats it. How about you? Taking a late-night request?<break time=200ms/>
Garia shook her head.<break time=200ms/>
Im just collecting payment. Whats with all the panic, though?<break time=200ms/>
She pointed to the group of Runners and staff of the Runners Guild who were standing around in a cluster at the counter, arguing and looking panicked. Fals made a face.<break time=200ms/>
You wont believe this, but for the last few days Lady Magnolias been asking for a delivery. Trouble is, she only wants one Runner to do it. Guess who?<break time=200ms/>
Garia didnt even need to think.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka. Oh. And what did the Guild tell her?<break time=200ms/>
Oh, I dont know the details<break time=200ms/>
Fals waved a hand self-deprecatingly, but that was just an act. Garia had no doubt he knew exactly what had been said, and probably had a part in shaping the message. <emphasis level="moderate">He</emphasis> was one of the most influential Runners in all the northern city-states and the local Guildmasters listened to him.<break time=200ms/>
The Guild told her Ryoka was indisposed. We kept offering replacement Runners, but Magnolia kept insisting that she only wanted Ryoka. And nowwell, it sounds like she came in person and demanded some answers just a few minutes ago. I was going to see what happened myself. Want to listen?<break time=200ms/>
Garia hesitated. It probably wasnt wise to put herself in the spotlightbut then again, Fals was the one in charge. So she nodded and followed him across the room.<break time=200ms/>
Fals whistled as he passed the board full of delivery requests. He stopped and pointed to one unmarked request Garia recognized.<break time=200ms/>
Wow. Look at that unmarked request. Whoevers posted it is offering twenty gold coins for a delivery.<break time=200ms/>
Garia peered at it.<break time=200ms/>
Its the same one I saw a week ago. Why hasnt anyone taken it yet? Id have thought you would have jumped at the opportunity, Fals.<break time=200ms/>
He shook his head.<break time=200ms/>
Are you kidding? I still want to live. Didnt you see the location? The High Passes. Thats a death trap for anyone.<break time=200ms/>
Even for you?<break time=200ms/>
He mock-glared at Garia.<break time=200ms/>
Even for me. For any Runner who takes it. I hope no ones stupid enough to head out there, but with that rewardI think we might lose a few.<break time=200ms/>
Then who will do it?<break time=200ms/>
Dunno. Maybe a Courier will do it if the reward keeps rising. But even a decently leveled [Runner] isnt nearly fast enough to avoid the monsters around there. Maybe the one who posted it will give up after a month or two.<break time=200ms/>
He shrugged.<break time=200ms/>
But frankly, even if they doubled the reward no sane Runner would risk a delivery like that. Profits important, but our lives are worth way more.<break time=200ms/>
Garia remembered something one of the adventurers had said. She frowned.<break time=200ms/>
Fals? I know youre one of our best Runners, but why arent there any older Runners than you? Youre only twenty two<break time=200ms/>
Twenty <emphasis level="moderate">three</emphasis>. Im getting old, Garia. Please dont rub it in.<break time=200ms/>
She blushed and tried not to stammer.<break time=200ms/>
Twenty three, then. But why arent there any other Runners? I know a lot of us die or get hurt, but surely there should be some more, right?<break time=200ms/>
Fals considered her question. He sighed, and raked his hand through his blonde locks.<break time=200ms/>
We dont have many experienced Runners because no one who does this job lives very long. Were the only people crazy enough to deliver. Most folks change classes after they earn enough.<break time=200ms/>
I heard people say Runners only care about money.<break time=200ms/>
Fals eyed her sternly.<break time=200ms/>
What kind of people have you been talking to, Garia?<break time=200ms/>
He didnt wait for her response.<break time=200ms/>
Never mind. Okay, sure, a lot of Runners are interested in the bottom line. But isnt that normal? Adventurers, shopkeepers, merchantseven nobles care about money. Why shouldnt we charge what we do and prioritize the best deliveries? We work a tough job! And we risk our lives every day, running from monsters, dealing with bad weather, natural disastersits enough to make most folk quit within their first week.<break time=200ms/>
He thumped at his chest.<break time=200ms/>
But wewere Runners. We dont quit! Everyone who makes it past a year is a real Runner, Garia. Were the people who keep the northern citiesno, the entire world connected. Without us, nothing would get done on time. So if people call us money-grubbers, well, let them. Weve got our own honor and we deserve every coin we get, am I right?<break time=200ms/>
His words lit a spark in Garias heart, and within the other Runners within earshot. She nodded enthusiastically as other Runners called out to Fals.<break time=200ms/>
Thats our lead Runner!<break time=200ms/>
No wonder youre the best in the cities!<break time=200ms/>
Persua appeared out of nowhere and purred at Fals. Garia jumped as the skinny girl smiled and fussed over him with her gaggle of Street Runners, edging Garia away.<break time=200ms/>
No wonder they call you Fleetfoot Fals!<break time=200ms/>
He grinned and shook her head.<break time=200ms/>
Thats an old nickname, guys. And anyways, Ryokas faster. I wonder if shes got some sort of skill?<break time=200ms/>
Persuas face soured. Garia scratched at her head.<break time=200ms/>
Now that you mention itshes never mentioned what level she is. She must be high-level, though.<break time=200ms/>
Well, she may be quick, but shes not running now, is she? Besides, shes so <emphasis level="moderate">un</emphasis>pleasant. Whod want a Runner who never smiles like her?<break time=200ms/>
Garia winced as Persua glared at her from behind Fals. For his part, Fals made a face and took a deliberate step next to Garia, preventing her from being shunted further away.<break time=200ms/>
Right. About that. I know Ryoka broke a few rules recently, but she <emphasis level="moderate">is</emphasis> a good runner. And we need all the Runners we can get.<break time=200ms/>
He smiled at Persua, and the younger girl sighed and turned red as he met her eyes.<break time=200ms/>
SoPersua. I dont want you or your friends to bother Ryoka again, okay?<break time=200ms/>
She sulked and pouted, but then gave Fals a sickly smile. He returned it with a slight wince that she didnt appear to notice.<break time=200ms/>
<emphasis level="moderate">Anything</emphasis> for you, Fals. Not that we did anything to Ryoka in the first place or anything. She just happened to have anaccident.<break time=200ms/>
Well, lets not have any more of those, are we clear? Were all on the same team, right?<break time=200ms/>
The other Runners nodded and voiced their agreement. Fals went around the room shaking hands and slapping Runners on the back. He eventually managed to get Persua to clear off by hinting that she and her cronies smelled sweaty, and finally he and Garia were left alone again. He sighed, but smiled at Garia.<break time=200ms/>
See what I mean, though? We cant be divided. Us Runners have to work together.<break time=200ms/>
Garia glared at Fals. She whispered out of the corner of her mouth.<break time=200ms/>
You <emphasis level="moderate">know</emphasis> she was behind it. Everyone does.<break time=200ms/>
He looked uncomfortable. Fals kicked at the ground with his expensive leather shoes and sighed. He combed his hair with one hand as he addressed Garia.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka broke a rule. They shouldnt have gone that far, but I did warn her. Weve got to work together, Garia. Even if one of us is faster, its better to share the wealth rather than compete. Youre new, but you understood that. Ryoka didnt and nowwell, now weve got trouble with Lady Magnolia <emphasis level="moderate">and</emphasis> were down a City Runner.<break time=200ms/>
This didnt sit well with Garia. She grimaced and stared hard at Fals. But when he met her gaze with a rueful smile and shrug she colored and looked away.<break time=200ms/>
I still dont like it. Persuas crazy. Ryoka wont be able to run for at least a <emphasis level="moderate">year</emphasis!< Even with potions to help her heal! Have you seen her leg?<break time=200ms/>
Fals hesitated.<break time=200ms/>
I heard it was just a bad break that the [Healers] cant fix right away. Is it worse than that?<break time=200ms/>
Garia looked miserable as she shook her head.<break time=200ms/>
I dont know. Im no expert, and shes got it wrapped in layers of bandages. They look magical though andand I met a mage who said that the only way shed get it healed was to pay hundreds of gold coins to a high-level [Healer].<break time=200ms/>
He <emphasis level="moderate">hissed</emphasis> through his teeth.<break time=200ms/>
Thats<emphasis level="moderate">no!</emphasis> I cant believe it! They <emphasis level="moderate">told</emphasis> me they wouldnt<break time=200ms/>
Garia interrupted Fals.<break time=200ms/>
You <emphasis level="moderate">knew? </emphasis>You knew andI cant believe you, Fals!<break time=200ms/>
Garias voice rose incredulously. She advanced on Fals, making fists with her hands. He raised his hands defensively as he backed away towards the counter.<break time=200ms/>
I had no choice! Look, you know what Persua and her friends are like. I told them not to do anything drastic, but even if Id stopped them, some other runners would have organized something. You <emphasis level="moderate">know</emphasis> the rules, Garia. Remember Perial, when he broke them?<break time=200ms/>
Garia remembered Perial. She didnt remember what hed done wrong, but she remembered that a bunch of Runners had dropped rusty nails in his path and forced him to run through them.<break time=200ms/>
Fals closed his eyes tightly and then opened them. He looked tired.<break time=200ms/>
Okay. That changes things. Look, Garia. IllIll talk to the Guildmaster after I see it in person. Persuas gone too far, even if Ryoka broke the rules.<break time=200ms/>
That still wont fix her leg.<break time=200ms/>
No, but its all I can do. Okay? And I dont know that any injury would really cost a hundred gold coins for a spell, Garia. Ill see Ryoka myself, but even if her bones are broken beyond a healing potions ability to repair, how bad could it really be?<break time=200ms/>
Its bad.<break time=200ms/>
Well see. I know a few good [Healers] and even a [Mage] that owes me a favor. If Ryokas really hurt that bad Ill call in a few favors and get the Guild to help out. Shell be on her feet by the end of the month, I promise. But can we see what the commotion is?<break time=200ms/>
Garia nodded. She felt a lot more upbeat with Fals promise. He always kept his word. She followed him to the counter as the Runners parted for him. Fals addressed a harried-looking receptionist at the counter.<break time=200ms/>
Whats going on? Is there more trouble with Magnolia?<break time=200ms/>
Trouble? Oh, theres been trouble alright.<break time=200ms/>
The receptionist laughed somewhat hysterically.<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia was here just half an hour ago. She came <emphasis level="moderate">in</emphasis> <emphasis level="moderate">person</emphasis> to complain to the Guildmaster, but he was out! She wanted to know where Ryoka was, and when she heard she was injured she was <emphasis level="moderate">not happy. </emphasis>She even suggested that she might stop ordering through our Guild altogether!<break time=200ms/>
Garia and Fals stared in horror at the receptionist. Lady Magnolia was one of the Guilds biggest patrons. Besides that, she was important. Even on the other end of the continent there were people who would know her name.<break time=200ms/>
Did she want anything else?<break time=200ms/>
She wanted to know where Ryoka was right now. Fortunately, we at least knew her address so she was <emphasis level="moderate">somewhat</emphasis> satisfied, but what will we do? If she stops ordering<break time=200ms/>
Garia interrupted urgently.<break time=200ms/>
Wait, she wanted to know where Ryoka was?<break time=200ms/>
The receptionist blinked at her. Normally Garia would have been brushed off in an instant, but Fals was with her.<break time=200ms/>
Yes, she wanted to know.<break time=200ms/>
And you <emphasis level="moderate">told</emphasis> her?<break time=200ms/>
The receptionist grew defensive at Garias accusatory tone.<break time=200ms/>
What? Its in the guilds best interest to keep her happy. If she wants to know where one of our Runners is, well tell her.<break time=200ms/>
But she wanted <emphasis level="moderate">Ryoka!</emphasis> And if she knows where she is, shell go and meet her!<break time=200ms/>
Fals groaned and pulled at his hair. He looked around frantically, but Magnolia was already long gone.<break time=200ms/>
Have you even <emphasis level="moderate">met</emphasis> Ryoka? Remember what happened when she met the Guildmaster? She doesnt respect anyone! If Magnolia shows up, shell probably throw her out of her room! Oror<break time=200ms/>
Punch her.<break time=200ms/>
Fals turned to Garia.<break time=200ms/>
No. She wouldnt do that. No ones crazy enough to punchshe wouldnt.<break time=200ms/>
Garia looked nervous.<break time=200ms/>
She punched a <emphasis level="moderate">Minotaur</emphasis> when he tried to invite himself into her room this morning.<break time=200ms/>
The receptionist and Fals both paled.<break time=200ms/>
Weve got to stop her. Or stop Ryoka.<break time=200ms/>
Follow me!<break time=200ms/>
Garia turned and raced out of the Guild, Fals hot on her heels. She wasnt one for prayers, but Garia still prayed that Ryoka would be civil, or at least acceptable before they got there. She didnt have much hope, though.<break time=200ms/>
She knew Ryoka.<break time=200ms/>
 <break time=200ms/>
—-<break time=200ms/>
 <break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia sat in the small, cramped bedroom of The Rats Tail, a moderately prosperous inn in the city of Celum. She clearly did not belong there. For one thing, her expensive, patterned, latticed, light pink dress with floral embroidery probably cost more than the inn itself.<break time=200ms/>
But she sat on the rickety chair the innkeeper had personally delivered to Ryokas room, looking perfectly content while she chatted with its inhabitant. Behind her, Resse the head maid stood in one corner of the room, glaring daggers at the poverty, the dirt under the windowsill, and Ryoka herself.<break time=200ms/>
My dear, I really was shocked to hear of your accident. Wont you tell me what happened?<break time=200ms/>
I got bored and played tag with a cart.<break time=200ms/>
You are <emphasis level="moderate">always</emphasis> full of unique answers, arent you Ryoka? I cant imagine how you can tell jokes in the face of such an injury.<break time=200ms/>
Not that Lady Magnolia had actually seen her injury, Ryoka reflected. She was lying on her bed, her sheets wrapped around her leg. Magnolia had walked in on her while she was resting and Ryoka hadnt yet unwrapped her protective cushion from her bad leg.<break time=200ms/>
As she shifted, Lady Magnolia raised a quick hand.<break time=200ms/>
No need to trouble yourself, Ryoka. I imagine you must be in quite a bit of pain, even if youve been using healing potions. No, I just wanted to talk to you.<break time=200ms/>
Offer me a deal, you mean.<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia blinked for a second, but in a flash she wore her same genuine smile again.<break time=200ms/>
You <emphasis level="moderate">are</emphasis> quick. Well, yes, to put it inelegantly I would like to offer you a deal. When I heard of your injury you may be sure I was astounded and not a little outragedespecially since I was given to understand that the event in question occurred only a few feet away from my mansion after you left.<break time=200ms/>
Took you a while to learn about it?<break time=200ms/>
Once again, the smile on Magnolias face flickered for the briefest instant before it was back in full force. Only someone watching for it would have noticed, and Ryoka had been watching.<break time=200ms/>
The Runners Guild has beenless than cooperative regarding your condition, as well as providing me with an explanation of how you were injured. I am still making discreet inquiries of my own, but I <emphasis level="moderate">will</emphasis> have answers, believe me. But that is not why Im here. I wish<break time=200ms/>
You want to offer me a deal to heal my leg, right?<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka shifted her weight in the bed discretely as Lady Magnolia blinked and recovered again. She ignored the maid glaring at her and reminded herself not to be so impatient. It would be funny if things didnt hurt so much. But astute noblewoman and political wrangler that Lady Magnolia might be, she wasnt nearly as unpredictable as she might like. Too bad nothing seemed to faze her either way.<break time=200ms/>
Well then, let me skip straight to the details, Ryoka. I understand that since you are still injured, healing potions arent working. As it so happens I havelet us call her a friend of minewho is able to cast [Restoration] and other spells of the 6th Tier.<break time=200ms/>
Ryokas face didnt change as she tried to understand what that meant. Clearly, it was impressive, but what was that about magic? Then she remembered.<break time=200ms/>
Tier Magic. It stood in stark contrast to the undisciplined magics, whatever that meant. But from what Ryoka had read in her extremely brief introduction to magic, Tiered Magic organized magic intiers.<break time=200ms/>
That was to say that a spell capable of being cast by all mages was generally thought of as 1st Tier Magic or 0 Tier Magic, while a spell that was 2nd Tier was more potent, requiring a better mage and longer periods of study to learn it. 3rd Tier magic was generally the bar for most mages, and they would know only one or two spells of that level. Anything higher got into the range of extremely powerful magic, exponentially stronger and just as hard to learn.<break time=200ms/>
That presumably meant that Magnolias friend was an incredible mage, but the book had said lower-level mages could cast higher Tier magic with enough practice and time. It also meant this mysterious friend was probably extremely powerful.<break time=200ms/>
Ryokas eyes narrowed. Magnolia smiled brightly at her.<break time=200ms/>
I guess I should be impressed? But if your friend is so powerful, why can’t I visit her myself?<break time=200ms/>
Well, shes <emphasis level="moderate">very</emphasis> busy as you might expect for someone with access to that kind of magic. And I will admitnormally receiving an audience with her, let alone persuading her to cast that kind of exhausting magic would be quite the feat.<break time=200ms/>
But you can do it.<break time=200ms/>
Let us just say that she owes me a few favors.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka rolled her eyes.<break time=200ms/>
And you want something in return. Get to the point.<break time=200ms/>
Behind Lady Magnolia, Ressa snapped at Ryoka.<break time=200ms/>
Be respectful! You are addressing a Lady of the five Founding Houses and<break time=200ms/>
Ressa, please.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka bared her teeth as Magnolia settled her maid back down. She stared into Ressas eyes as the stern-looking maid attempted to vaporize her with her own stare.<break time=200ms/>
Can your maid fight?<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia blinked in bemusement.<break time=200ms/>
Ressa is quite skilled in a number of areas, my dear Ryoka. Among them is a talent for handling untoward guests, I must admit.<break time=200ms/>
And dealing with filth that approaches my lady.<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia <emphasis level="moderate">tsked</emphasis> in disapproval, but Ryoka just shifted her weight on the bed.<break time=200ms/>
Bring it.<break time=200ms/>
The look in Ressas eyes suggested that if Lady Magnolia stepped out of the roomor even turned her head for a minute, quite a lot of violence would be brought. But once again, Magnolia waved a hand at her.<break time=200ms/>
I wouldnt try anything, dear Ressa. I do believe it might backfire on you, and besides, I dont think that Ryoka Griffin would learn or even be humbled by a beating however soundly administered.<break time=200ms/>
The look in Ressas eye suggested she would be willing to try. But she subsided and Ryoka turned her attention back to Magnolia.<break time=200ms/>
So if I dont accept your generous offer youll bewhat? Offended?<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia laughed again.<break time=200ms/>
My dear, Im only offended by those who have nothing to offer me. No, I imagine it would take some doing for you to cause me any real offense. If you refuse I would merely be<break time=200ms/>
Annoyed?<break time=200ms/>
Disappointed. Very greatly so. After all, it is in my best interest and yours for you to be running again. For you it is your livelihood, and for mewell, I suspect you would be far more amicable when youre not grumpy and irritable with pain.<break time=200ms/>
Maybe. Maybe not. Can you just tell me what you want in return already?<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia sighed.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka, I have to ask. I have a number of skills, one of which is [Charming Demeanor], yet it seems to have no effect on you. Ive dealt with stubborn generals and obnoxious Dragons and had more of an effect. Would you care to explain your extraordinary resilience?<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka shrugged.<break time=200ms/>
Ive met people more charming than you. I didnt like them either. What do you want?<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia pursed her lips in gentle vexation.<break time=200ms/>
Well. Im prepared to pay whatever my friend desires and have her over here in a blink of an eye, even if I must pay for teleportation. But I do want something Ryoka. Nothing too arduousmerely answers to a number of burning questions I find myself saddled with.<break time=200ms/>
Answers. How many?<break time=200ms/>
How many? Ryoka my dear, I would hope for what I offer I would be allowed to ask as many questions as I dare. Not to put a fine point on it, but a spell to heal your leg is <emphasis level="moderate">costly</emphasis>. Arent a few answers worth the price of asking?<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka shook her head.<break time=200ms/>
Not to me.<break time=200ms/>
For once, Lady Magnolia seemed off-balance. She exchanged a quick glance with her maid.<break time=200ms/>
Then what did you have in mind?<break time=200ms/>
Twenty answers to twenty questions.<break time=200ms/>
You must be joking. Ryoka my dear<break time=200ms/>
Im not going to tell you everything. Id answer a limited number of questions, but not everything.<break time=200ms/>
For the first time, Lady Magnolia seemed genuinely shocked. She cast around for a reply.<break time=200ms/>
You know, it may have been naïve of me, but I had assumed coming here that I would be able to name my own price for discrete assistance. But you have a price of your own, I take it. Ryoka, is your leg worth say, four hundred questions?<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka gritted her teeth.<break time=200ms/>
No more than eightyno, forty questions.<break time=200ms/>
…I cannot accept that. Even two hundred questionsdo you harbor such dire secrets that you must put a price on this?<break time=200ms/>
If youve got to ask, you know the answer. Forty questions. Take it or leave it.<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia blew out her breath in exasperation.<break time=200ms/>
I am in shock. Truly. And if I called your bluff?<break time=200ms/>
Ryokas eyed narrowed. She removed the sheets around her leg and swung herself out of bed. Her flesh <emphasis level="moderate">screamed</emphasis> at her, but the bindings on her leg held it in place.<break time=200ms/>
Theres the door.<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia didnt move. Her eyes were transfixed on Ryokas bound leg, and even Ressa looked ill. But Magnolia was genuinely shocked. She knew what bad injuries looked like.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka. <emphasis level="moderate">How</emphasis> are you still moving around on that leg?<break time=200ms/>
Magic. Duh.<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia blinked. She looked up and met Ryokas eyes.<break time=200ms/>
And how many healing potions have you used up so far?<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka shrugged.<break time=200ms/>
Forty? Fifty? I lost count.<break time=200ms/>
And youve been sitting here, without going to see a proper [Healer]? Why?<break time=200ms/>
Not enough money.<break time=200ms/>
And you didnt visit me and request my assistance because?<break time=200ms/>
If I tried to reach you, theyd run me over again.<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolias frowned darkly.<break time=200ms/>
No one would dare assault a guest on my doorstep.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka shrugged again.<break time=200ms/>
It might happen. And I dont want to lose both legs.<break time=200ms/>
I cannot believethis goes beyond a mere act of sabotage. Whoever did this intended to cripple you. I trust you know this? Even an experienced [Healer] would have had a near-impossible task saving your leg.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka grinned. Her face was deathly pale, but she kept herself propped up on her elbows.<break time=200ms/>
They wanted to amputate it right away. I said no.<break time=200ms/>
And you wont accept my offer?<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia stared at Ryoka. Her eyes pierced the young woman to her core, searching for the truth. That was what Ryoka was afraid of. But she met the eyes and shook her head.<break time=200ms/>
Forty questions. Thats all Id answer. A finite number, not everything.<break time=200ms/>
Once again, she received the impression shed truly surprised Lady Magnolia as the older lady hesitated and seemed to grapple with Ryokas offer. But the noblewoman shook her head at last.<break time=200ms/>
A good gambler knows when to bet and when to fold. My offer stands. Answers to all my questions and I will have your leg healed by the end of the hour, my word on it.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka bit the inside of her lip until it bled and tried not to let her disappointment show on her face. But then, Magnolia would sense it either way, right? But she didnt say anything. Instead, Ryoka collapsed onto her bed and stared up at the ceiling.<break time=200ms/>
Magnolia stared at her, still seemingly in a state of shock.<break time=200ms/>
Incredible. And you still refuse. What secrets do you hold that would be worth that price, Ryoka Griffin?<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka didnt answer. After a moment, Lady Magnolia stood up.<break time=200ms/>
Very well. I believe you will change your mind. I will wait for your response.<break time=200ms/>
Still, Ryoka didnt respond. She heard rustling, and then Magnolia pressed something cold and hard into her hand. Ryoka raised her head slightly and saw it was a strange medallionbronze and seemingly not that expensive, but inlaid with a precious blue sapphire in the center of the metalwork.<break time=200ms/>
Simply shatter the gem in the center and I will know you accept my terms.<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia stared down at Ryoka as the young woman lay on her bed. She didnt even glance up at the noblewoman. Instead, Ryoka smiled bitterly at the ceiling.<break time=200ms/>
You play hardball, huh?<break time=200ms/>
I gamble with lives and opportunity, Ryoka my dear. And I am convinced that this is a gamble worth taking. Accept my offer.<break time=200ms/>
Dont let the door hit you on the way out.<break time=200ms/>
More silence, and then Ryoka sensed Lady Magnolia move towards the door. Ressa held it open for her, but the noblewoman paused in the doorway for a long minute.<break time=200ms/>
Is information truly worth such a high price?<break time=200ms/>
At last, Ryoka raised her head. She saw Lady Magnolia staring at her with what looked like genuine worry. Ryoka grinned. Her brow was covered with sweat and she was pale under her tan. She wasnt really grinning, either. Just showing a lot of teeth.<break time=200ms/>
You want trust. Thats too high a price for me.<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia paused and opened her mouth. Then she shook her head.<break time=200ms/>
I will wait. But hurry, Ryoka. Your time is running out.<break time=200ms/>
The door closed. Ryoka was left alone. She covered her eyes.<break time=200ms/>
Damnit. Gods damn it all.<break time=200ms/>
 <break time=200ms/>
—-<break time=200ms/>
 <break time=200ms/>
Im an idiot. I have to cover my eyes to keep the tears from leaking. Im such a complete and utter, stubborn idiot.<break time=200ms/>
I should have accepted her offer immediately. Noeven if Magnolia wanted me to be her slave, or her maid, or to work for her for ten years I would have accepted her offer in a heartbeat.<break time=200ms/>
But she wanted me to tell her the truth. Damn it. Damn her and her insight. Thats the one thing I cant give her. Ever.<break time=200ms/>
My leg is agony. But my heart is ice. And now that Ive been given the offer, the path is clear. Two roads stretch out before me, and a world waits upon my choice.<break time=200ms/>
Is that dramatic? Its too dramatic. But it is true.<break time=200ms/>
Stand up. I need another healing potion. My leg hurtsI need a clear head for it.<break time=200ms/>
I get up and open the chest. Pain shoots through my bad leg. Three healing potions. Damn it, again. I cant waste them. Not if<break time=200ms/>
Well, if I refuse theres no point to them. Theyre weak things, anyways. But they told me a stronger healing potion would start growing each fragment of bone out of my skin, and that would destroy my leg beyond any healing.<break time=200ms/>
Something. Oh. I see at the bottom of the chest the only thing I really own in this world. From my world. It lies at the bottom of my chest. Useless, without power. At least the earbuds are still attached, but again, useless without electricity.<break time=200ms/>
I look at the piece of plastic and metal lying at the bottom of the chest. Would she accept that instead? But Id still have to tell her what it is, and that could be as potentially dangerous as<break time=200ms/>
No. No, its worthless in any case. If there was power left in it I might be able to make the trade butno. Its information she wants. And that price is just too high for me to pay.<break time=200ms/>
Information.<break time=200ms/>
The word rots on my tongue. It sounds so stupid, so simple and easy to give away when you say it like that. And it would be simple for me to agree to answer however many questions.<break time=200ms/>
Except that Magnolia can read minds. Or sense untruths. And shes cunning, smart enough to keep asking questions. If I gave her unlimited answers shed have the entire truth eventually.<break time=200ms/>
I could lie. But shed sense it if I didnt intend to fulfill my bargain. Trapped, again.<break time=200ms/>
Pride be damned. Ill go back and beg her if need be. The costIll think of it later. But even if it means selling part of my soul or my worlds secrets, I will run again.<break time=200ms/>
Butno. I cant do that. No, never. Because if she asks questions<break time=200ms/>
If she asks questions shell learn about my world. Good? Thats fine. Even if she knows, can she get there so easily? I dont think it matters. If someone could travel between worlds so easily, wed already know about it. Maybe she could, but we have guns and way more technology that she does.<break time=200ms/>
But thats the catch, isnt it? We have technology, and if she asks more questions, shell know about our worlds technology. Not just things like hygiene or bacteria, but the things that should never be told. Secrets, jumps forward in capability that would make any nation a superpower in an instant.<break time=200ms/>
Gunpowder. Firearms. Germ warfare. Steam power, electrical power, locomotion. Everything from interrogation techniques to how to build a tank or a bomb. Nuclear weapons.<break time=200ms/>
Does it sound stupid to say it like that? I dont know how to make nukes. But I do know what goes into gunpowder. I aced chemistry class. I know exactly how a turbine works, and Im pretty damn sure I remember all of the techniques the FBI illegally used on terrorists.<break time=200ms/>
Damn it. Its a moral choice, isnt it? Lose my leg, or give away the secrets of death and destruction. If it were anyone else I could lie, or tell only small truths. But she can read my damn mind. And I know exactly where to gather all the ingredients of gunpowder. And guns wouldnt be hard to make, not in this world.<break time=200ms/>
Lady Magnolia. I know nothing about her. Just rumors and that shes a powerful and influential lady with wealth and connections. Even if she appears niceespecially if she appears niceI have no way of knowing if shed use that power to help or harm.<break time=200ms/>
No. Its simpler than that.<break time=200ms/>
Even if I could trust her, the secret would spread. Thats how it works. Shed want to see a demonstration, and someone would put the pieces together. Ressa, her maid, maybe. Sooner or later technology would spread. Id be responsible for bringing guns into the world. And maybe its not that far away from that level of technology already but<break time=200ms/>
Belfast. Beruit. Phnom Penh. All flesh is grass.<break time=200ms/>
When I was a girl, I went to the Newseum in Washington D.C. I saw the pictures on the walls. I looked at the children, the dying and the dead. My dad thought I was too young to understand.<break time=200ms/>
All flesh is grass. The War Photographer by Carol Ann Duffy. Is it a straight line between bringing the capabilities of gunpowder to the world and terrible war? No. But where there is knowledge, there is power. And even if she used her power to help her nation, that would only lead to war in the end.<break time=200ms/>
Napalm. Mixed petroleum with a natural or synthesized rubber like latex. It wouldnt be hard to create the same kind of thing. Not with Magnolias influence.<break time=200ms/>
I want to run. I want to walk again.<break time=200ms/>
Im no Walter White. But I remember too much. Too much National Geographic and other shows about the world. Not a perfect memory. But too close.<break time=200ms/>
Damn it. I cant do it. I dont want to be the one who creates a Hitler or gives another whitewoman a gun and a mandate to conquer the world. But I want to run.<break time=200ms/>
I cant figure it out. I cant decide. I waited a weeka damn <emphasis level="moderate">week</emphasis> for her to arrive. In pain and fear. And now that she offered me what I was dreaming of I should have leapt at it. But I hesitate. I draw back.<break time=200ms/>
I sit on the edge of the abyss and wonder if my soul burns well in hell. Its not fair. All I ever want to do was run. I dont want to lose my leg. I want to run. I want to live. I want to walk.<break time=200ms/>
I dont want to see the child sitting alone. I dont want to see the vulture. I dont want it to be my fault.<break time=200ms/>
Alone, I sit in my room, sitting with the fate of two worlds in my hands. This worlds, and my world. I live to run. My legs are what define me.<break time=200ms/>
The medallion is cold in my hands. I could shatter the gem in an instant. Grind it against the floorboards. It would be so quick, so easy.<break time=200ms/>
It would<break time=200ms/>
The door opens. I look up. A face like perfection and a dream stares at me. Half perfection, half mortal. The cruelest of both worlds. Ceria Springwalker.<break time=200ms/>
She hesitates, and then steps into the room. I expect hollow words and hollower promises. I expect to be let down, or to feel nothing but despair. But she doesnt bring any of that.<break time=200ms/>
She brings salvation.<break time=200ms/>
 <break time=200ms/>
—-<break time=200ms/>
 <break time=200ms/>
I know its bad.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka sat on the bed. Ceria stared at her leg, and then looked away.<break time=200ms/>
Ive seen an injury like that before. Im aware it cant be healed so easily. Im not sure if your friend really understood<break time=200ms/>
She doesnt. It doesnt matter. She cant help. Neither can you.<break time=200ms/>
We owe you a debt. You might not understand it, but Calruz hired every member of the Horns of Hammerad because we believe in honor. If we can help, we will.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka bared her teeth.<break time=200ms/>
Got a few hundred gold coins?<break time=200ms/>
No. Thats beyond us, frankly. Even if we sold our armor and weapons  and Calruz might, to impress you  I doubt wed be able to get close to a [Healer] of that level. Theyre in constant demand. Thousands camp around the home of a famous [Healer] in Tenbault each day, hoping shell tend to them. Even if we had the money they charge it would take a miracle.<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka grunted. Her hand was clutching a medallion Ceria recognized. A simple spell was embedded in the gem in the center. She made no comment. Instead, Ceria looked at Ryoka. Ryoka gazed back.<break time=200ms/>
What the young woman saw, Ceria could guess. A half-breed, perhaps. A memory of what was lost, or maybe she just saw a mage, someone who pursued strange goals few understood. It didnt matter. And for some reason, Ceria thought that the Runner known as Ryoka Griffin looked at her differently than the rest. But duty was duty. Honor was honor.<break time=200ms/>
My peo<emphasis level="moderate">I</emphasis> dont trust the nobility.<break time=200ms/>
Ceria glanced sidelong at Ryoka, as if hoping for a conformation. Ryoka grunted.<break time=200ms/>
I dont trust anyone.<break time=200ms/>
I know that Lady Magnolia offered yousomething. I saw her on the way in. You might want to accept, but all deals have a price. Even if she doesnt say, shell want something.<break time=200ms/>
I know.<break time=200ms/>
A spell is probably the only way to cure your leg. But theres magic that she offers, and then theresanother way.<break time=200ms/>
Another way?<break time=200ms/>
Ryoka looked at Ceria. Her eyes seemed to pierce the young half-elf to her core. Ceria Springwalker had lived for over sixty years, but she hadnt ever seen someone as desperate as Ryoka.<break time=200ms/>
Tell me.<break time=200ms/>
The eyes seemed to be boring a path straight into her soul. Ceria took a deep breath.<break time=200ms/>
How do you feel about necromancy?<break time=200ms/>
 <break time=200ms/>

<break time=200ms/>
</speak>